



SANTOSH D

Charlotte, NC 28262♦ (510) 674-8380 ♦ santosh.doulager@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

DevOps Infrastructure Engineer with 9 years of overall I.T experience in the areas of Azure, Middleware administration, Linux Administration, Release Management, Kubernetes, Docker, Ansible including migrating applications from on-premises to Azure. Possess strong commitment to the team environment and ability to work independently.

SKILLS -

Cloud Services: Azure (App Services, VM, Storage,

VPN, NSG, IAM), AWS (EC2,

S3, Cloud Watch)

Application Servers: WebSphere, WebLogic, JBoss,

Apache Tomcat.

Webservers: Apache, IBM HTTP Server.

CI/CD: Jenkins, Azure Pipelines.

Container Orchestration: Docker, Kubernetes

(AKS)

Scripting: Bash, PowerShell, YAML.

Monitoring: Dynatrace, Azure Application Insights

IAAC: Terraform

Security: CyberArk, Okta Verify, Duo.

Operating System: Windows, UNIX, RHEL, Ubuntu,

CentOS

Code Management: Git, GitHub, Azure DevOps

Databases: SQL.

Ticketing: Service Now, Atlassian Jira, Kanban

Configuration Management: Ansible

Languages: C, Python

Logging: SPLUNK

Protocols: TCP/IP, HTTP/HTTPS, SOAP, FTP,

SSL/TLS.

Other Tools: Yammer, Smart Dispatch, ForgeRock,

Kanban board, Stone Branch, Kenna Security, SwissRe

Magnum, Confluence.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Installation & Administration
- Configuration, Deploying & Upgrading
- Automation
- Troubleshooting & Monitoring

- Diagnostic Skills
- Scripting
- Documentation & Report

CERTIFICATIONS —

- Azure (AZ-104) Administrator associate
- Azure (AZ-400) DevOps Engineer
- ITIL v3 Certified.

WORK HISTORY

DevOps Infrastructure Engineer/Middleware, April 2022 – Present

Client: Equitable - Charlotte, NC

Employer: Tata Consultancy Services

- Design, deploy, manage, administering, and configuring Middleware Infrastructure platforms in Hybrid Environment and Involved in Lift and Shift of application to Azure.
- Design, implement and maintain automation for a variety of middleware technologies through Ansible
 automation tool by writing the appropriate playbooks and roles and create templates and inventories
 based on requirement.
- Installed, Configured, and Administration of **IBM WebSphere Application Server 8.x/8.5.x/9.x** (ND and BASE), **WebLogic Application Server 12c**, **JBOSS EAP 6.4**, **Apache Tomcat 8.5.x.**, **Apache 2.2/2.4**, **IBM HTTP Server**.
- Led the migration of middleware on-premises systems to the cloud, resulting in significant cost savings and improved reliability.
- Created and maintained automated deployment pipelines using **Azure DevOps** and related tools.
- Migrated on-premises workloads to Azure using tools such as Azure Migrate and Azure Site Recovery.
- Worked closely with development teams to ensure smooth and efficient software releases.
- Proficient with container orchestration technologies (**Docker, Kubernetes**).
- Utilized **Azure App Services** to deploy and host web applications.
- Identify, analyze, and resolve infrastructure vulnerabilities and application deployments.
- Good knowledge on Implementing Azure Kubernetes Services to deploy and manage containerized
 applications and Azure Networking solutions including virtual networks, network security groups, and
 load balancers.

- Knowledge on Azure Managed Identity to secure access to resources and simplify the management of identities.
- Used CyberArk to secure Linux servers.
- Good Knowledge on Automation testing including Unit testing, penetration testing, performance testing.
- Monitored and optimized the performance of Azure-based solutions using **Dynatrace** and **Azure** Application Insights.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to troubleshoot and debug issues.
- Co-ordination with Product Managers/Owners, Development teams, and other Operations teams to schedule and support software releases.
- Participated in agile development process, including planning, stand-ups, and retrospectives.
- Worked closely with development teams to ensure smooth and efficient software releases.
- Co-ordination with Customer Support, Operations, and Customers to resolve issues
- Created and maintained documentation for all aspects of the release process.
- Establish and improve processes and practices to ensure timely delivery and high-quality work.

Environment: Ansible, Azure, Kubernetes, Docker, Shell Scripting, Service Now, Kanban Board, CyberArk, Apache 2.2/2.4, SQL, WebSphere Application Servers 9.x.

Infrastructure Engineer/Middleware, March 2017 – Mar 2022

Client: Equitable – Syracuse, NY

Employer: Aplomb Technologies Inc.

- Installed, Configured, and Administration of IBM WebSphere Application Server 8.x/8.5.x/9.x (ND and BASE), WebLogic Application Server 12c, JBOSS EAP 6.4, Apache Tomcat 8.5.x., Apache 2.2/2.4, IBM HTTP Server.
- Deployed applications in domain and clustered environments of WebSphere Application Server, WebLogic Application Server, and Apache Tomcat Server.
- Monitor Performance of the middleware and Linux applications infrastructure environment using
 Splunk and Dynatrace. Develop methods and practices to recover the environments from various
 failures within the SLA's.
- Involved in performance tuning of JVM and used Garbage collection for better performance.

- Work Closely with the various IT and business teams to troubleshoot and resolve issues in a timely
 manner. Capture, review and analyze application logs, network, and stack traces, etc., for
 troubleshooting application performance.
- Provide Root Cause Analysis for issues related to webservers and application servers.
- Configuring global security and remediate vulnerabilities following IBM recommendations. Work with **F5** networks big IP for high availability load balancing of traffic to various internet web services.
- Fixed vulnerabilities related to Java version on WAS reported by Kenna Security.
- Worked closely with **Stone Branch** team to schedule jobs.
- Configured **SwissRe Magnum** on Apache Tomcat.
- Upgraded IBM ODM version to 8.10.
- Password remediation for weak passwords on Linux Servers.
- Created **SSL/TLS Certificates** for communication between web servers and application servers.
- Troubleshoot application slowness and unavailability issues in DEV, QA, UAT and PROD. Generate
 heap dumps, thread dumps, and core dumps. Analyze heap dumps through Heap Analyzer and java
 cores through thread dump analyzer.
- Used **Kanban Board** to update the User Stories and features in Azure VSTS.
- Document installation, configuration, monitoring, design procedure, deployment, stress, and failure test scenarios.
- Used Service Now to create and manage Change Requests and Incidents.
- Created users, roles and assigned them to appropriate groups.
- Provided 24x7 on-call support for production / non-production environments.

Environment: Ansible, Azure, WebSphere Application Server 6.x/7.x/8.x/9.x, WebSphere Portal Server 8.x, WebLogic Application Server12c, JBoss EAP 6.x, Smart Dispatch, Dynatrace, Splunk, Redhat6.x,7.x, IBM HTTP, Apache 2.2.x/2.4, J2EE, Oracle 10g/11g, Shell scripting, CyberArk, Service Now.

Middleware Administrator, July 2016 – Feb 2017

Client: GE Digital - San Ramon, CA

Employer: MPRSoft Inc

- Responsible for versioning the source code, releasing binary files, creating, and applying labels on source files and release files.
- Led Jenkins continuous integration server installation and configuration for all GIT Repositories.
- Automated application packaging and deployment.

- Managed multiple GIT repositories with a version control wrapper tool REPO.
- Used Confluence to Document the work.
- Established coding standards and enforced them through automated tools.
- Configured multiple Linux slaves for Jenkins's master to distribute the load across a Farm of machines.
- Configured Jenkins jobs to Implement Nightly builds on daily basis and generate change log that includes changes happened from last 24 hours.
- Connected continuous integration system with GIT version control repository and continually build as the check-in's come from the developer.
- Created Multiple Shell (bash) scripts for build automation and deployment.
- Scheduled corn jobs to run automated jobs on regular basis.
- Documented the SCM process and policies of the company and recommended some process changes.
- Responsible for writing the Release Notes, documenting all useful info about the release: software versions, changes implemented in the release, Defects fixed, Labels applied etc.
- Coordinated software development teams and QA teams on issues and solved the problems.
- Responsible for the Memory Leak and Load Balancing on Jenkins Server.

Environment: Tomcat Application Server, GIT, Confluence, Jenkins, Shell Scripting, Redhat5.x,6.x,7.x, Oracle 10g/11g.

Service Delivery Associate, February 2013 – Dec 2014

Unisys India – Hyderabad

- Involved in gathering, analyzing, and documenting business requirements, functional requirements and data specifications for **Business Objects Universes** and Reports.
- Generated Reports using SAP BO and Microsoft Excel.
- Exclusive Experience in SAP BW connectivity with Universe Designer and Business objects **Info view** using the SAP Integration Kit.
- Developed provider scorecard reports using **Webi** as the reporting tool.
- Experienced in Developing Reports and Customizing reports using Alerts, Breaks, and Filters and Sorts
 etc.
- Developed dashboard reports using Reporting Services, Report Model and ad-hoc reporting using Report Builder.
- Experience in creating Parameterized reports and Linked reports with thorough knowledge of report serving architecture. (Table, chart, and matrix report).

- Involved in designing, developing, debugging, and testing of reports in SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS).
- Experience in configuring and deploying **SSRS** reports onto Microsoft Office SharePoint Server.
- Developing and implementing plans for improving Business Intelligence & Performance via Operational Reporting, SLA & Service Excellence Reporting across the Global Clients.
- Managing the reporting and analytics platform(s) to ensure that scheduled jobs are successfully run, and analytics data aligns to timeliness / completeness requirements.
- Developed ad-hoc schedules as and when required to accommodate requirements churns.
- Proactively monitored and reported the progress to stakeholders.
- Experience in strategically influencing the team and stakeholders while maintaining a high level of business partnering.

Environment: SAP Business Objects, Service Now, MS SQL, MS Excel, SSRS.

Data Analyst, Oct 2011 – Jan 2013

Vasyaa BI Solutions & Services, Hyderabad

- Creating internal tools for Data Labelling.
- Gathered requirements for building Crystal reports.
- Developed Dashboards using Xcelsius.
- Worked on scope scripts for job submissions.
- Responded to associate support requests in real time providing education to Associates with the goal of achieving first contact resolution, as well as a remarkable, reproducible Customer experience.
- Derived opportunities for efficiency through daily floor observations.
- Built and maintained tools, analytics, and reporting while leading multiple analysis efforts, providing analysis that is insightful and consumable by internal audiences.

Environment: SAP Business Objects, Xcelsius, MS SQL, MS Excel, SSRS.

EDUCATION

- Bachelor's in Information Technology, Jawaharlal Technological University, India (2006-2010).
- Master's in Computer Science at Northwestern Polytechnic University, CA (Jan 2015 –May 2016).
- Master's in Business Administration at Campbellsville University, Kentucky (July 2019 Oct 2020)